Zaven Snkhchyan

• Email: snkhchyan.zaven@protonmail.com

Github: adsellor Phone: +37441222341

About

I'm a Full Stack developer, specializing in React, React Native, Flutter, NodeJs. I like to tinker with new technologies and build experiments with them. In my free time, I learn quantum computing, read about machine learning and theoretical physics.

Education

American University of Armenia, Yerevan, Armenia (2016)

South Haven High School, MI, USA (2015 - 2016)

High School of Vanadzor State Pedagogic University, Vanadzor, Armenia (2013 - 2015)

Pablo Tichina Basic School, Vanadzor, Armenia (2004 - 2013)

Experience

Freelance Front-End Developer - Gruv (May 2020 - July 2020)

As a freelance front-end developer, I built a new component system with modular architecture, using React, to implement the redesign with Material UI.

React Native consultant - Umath (March 2020 - May 2020)

As a React-Native consultant, I've helped the Umath development team to launch the initial version of the application. I've also integrated In-App-Purchases and designed a sustainable state management architecture.

Software Engineer - Noomee (March 2019 - July 2020)

As a Lead Software Engineer at Noomee, I am in charge of the app development, which includes the mobile application (Dart/Flutter) and the backend (NodeJS/TypeScript). I also manage the app lifecycle, which includes CI/CD, monitoring, logging and analyzing.

JavaScript course instructor - ISTC (June 2018 - August 2018)

During 3 months of intensive JavaScript training, students learned basics of computer programming with JavaScript, worked with HTML/CSS and built their own projects using React.

Mobile Developer - Hexa Venture Studio (Dec 2017 - April 2018)

Used React Native to develop a cross-platform mobile application, with embedded pre-trained image classification model, that helped users to conveniently manage their gallery.

Front-End Developer - ApolloBytes (August 2017 - Dec 2017)

As a member of the "Core Team", I used React and VueJS to build the Core Component library and its architecture, which was used by more than 30 in-house developers to effortlessly bootstrap applications.

Open Source Software

Co-authored

foxx_services: A collection of various ArangoDB foxx microservices built with TypeScript, used to separate Data Access Layer from the main application. Microservices include auth, interactions and a shared services.

Authored

quick_notes: A Flutter based application that uses Firebase's image recognition kit, to turn images into text-based editable notes.

Open Health: Project built during 24 hour "Open Health" hackathon, that uses React Native and NodeJS to manage queus and store patient history.

Languages

Human

- Armenian Native
- English Fluent
- Russian Fluent

Machine

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Dart
- Elm
- Elixir

Skills

Libraries and Frameworks

- React (NextJS)
- React-Native
- Flutter
- NodeJs (Express, Koa)
- VueJS (NuxtJS)
- SvelteJS

Databases

- PostgreSQL
- MySql
- SQLite
- ArangoDB
- Neo4j
- RealmJS
- Redis

Cloud services

• AWS - EC2, Lambda, RDS, Route53, Cognito.